爱达荷
5,6,7,8...
Five, six, seven, eight...
9, 10.
nine, 10.
I always know where I am by the way the road looks.
看这条路我就知道我在哪里
Like I just know that I've been here before.
我知道我来过这里
I just know that I've been stuck here...
我知道我被困在这
like this one fucking time before, you know that?
就像以前一样，你知道吗?
Yeah.
对
There's not another road anywhere that looks like this road.
绝对找不到跟这条路一样的
I mean, exactly like this road.
我是说跟这条路一模一样
It's one kind of place.
绝无仅有的，就这一样
One of a kind.
Like someone's face.
像一个人的脸
Like a fucked-up face.
一张乱七八糟的脸
Where do you think you're running, man?
你想往哪里跑?
你这个笨蛋，我们都困在这
We're stuck here together, you shit.
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be all right.
别担心，没事了
I know. It's okay.
我知道，会没事的
I know, you're sorry. I know.
不是你的错，我明白
The cattle are prowlin' The coyotes are howlin'
Way out where the doggies bawl
Where spurs are a-jinglin', a cowboy is singin'
This lonesome cattle call
He rides in the saddle till his day's work is done
片名：我私人的爱达荷 （又译：男人的一半还是男人／不羁的天空）
And he rounds up the cattle each fall
Walt.
华特!华特
- Walt. - Yeah, Mike?
什么事?
You think, um, that you could spot me 10 more dollars?
你可以再借我十块钱吗?
Ten dollars? What's the matter? You can't get it from your dad?
十块，怎么了?
你干嘛不跟你老爸要?
My dad and I don't get along too well. You know that, Walt.
我老爸跟我相处得不好
We're not getting along that well either now, are we?
你知道的，华特
我们也相处得不好
No. We don't get along too well...
不，我们没办法相处得来
or else he wouldn't have gone out and drowned himself at Boxcar Canyon.
要不然他不会去跳下峡谷去
- Again? - Yeah.
你听说了
对啊!他掉到水里去了
He hit the water this time?
- He survived the first time. This time... - Oh, God.
他第一次没死，这一次
You're the only one I can ask. You know that, Walt.
奥，老弟
Please! I'll owe you a date. How about that?
华特，我只能跟你开口，拜托
我欠你一次好不好?
I'll owe you a date. Please.
算我欠你一次，求求你
Oh, God, crying tears. Hold on.
奥，老天爷，又是哭又是泪
Here you go.
等会，拿去
多谢
Thanks.
Don't worry.
别担心，没事了
Everything's gonna be all right.
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be all right.
别担心，没事了
Here. Now, mind the carpet. It's white.
小心这地布，白色的
Give me your shoes. Give me your shoes.
把鞋子给我
我的鞋子
Mmm. Mmm.
Okay, just a sec.
好，等一下
Put these on... so you don't make a mess.
穿上，免得弄脏
I am so lucky.
我真幸运
I was born on April 4, 1944.
我在l944年4月4日诞生
That's 4-4-44.
把所有的4加起来就成了l6
If you add that up, it comes to 16.
One, six.
1和6
One plus six is seven.
1加6等于7，最幸运的号码
Luckiest number of all.
- You know your math. - It's more than math, Mike.
你的算术真有一套
那不只是算术而己，麦可
It's...
简直是完美
immaculate perfection.
Oh.
老天
Boy, this place is a mess.
这地方真是乱的可以
Yeah, let's make it immaculate.
是啊
让我们整理得完美
- Okay. - Okay.
好啊
好
Deep night
Stars in the sky above
Moonlight
Lighting our place of love
Night winds
Seem to have gone to rest
Two eyes
Faster, little Dutch boy.
快点，用力点
Harder.
Yeah, that sound. That sound.
对，那声音，就是那声音
Vow that you'll love me always
And be mine alone
- I'm all done. - Deep night
我做完了
And now, my lucky 44th...
现在我第44位幸运荷兰仔
little Dutch boy...
you must scrub...
你得刷刷我这老骨头
Daddy Carroll.
This chick's living in a new car ad.
这马子真像新车广告中的女郎
简直像梦一般
Feels like a dream.
A girl never picks me up, much less a pretty, rich girl.
快没有女孩看上我
更别说漂亮有钱的女孩
They don't? I don't know why that is.
他们从不挑你?
那我就不清楚什么原因
This is a nice home.
这个家很棒，你住这里?
- Do you live here? - Yes.
是啊
I don't blame you.
真不赖啊
Oh.
Hey.
What up, Scott? What up, Gary?
是你史考特!
是你盖端!
哈，是麦可
Hey, it's Mikey the dike.
You men make yourselves comfortable.
你们自己照顾一下
I'll be right back.
我马上就来
There are cokes in the refrigerator. Help yourselves.
冰箱有可乐，自己来
她很酷
She's cool. She just likes to have three guys 'cause it takes her a while to get warmed up.
她喜欢和叁个男人一起来
因为她要好一段时间进入情况
It's normal. Nothing kinky.
那很正常，不稀奇
Yeah.
是啊
Hey, dude, did you get into that Sinéad O'Connor concert last night?
小于，你昨晚听演唱会没
什么?
- What? To... To the Sinéad... - The chick with the bald head.
就是那个光头的马子
I-I've never been to a concert before, dude.
我从来没有听过演唱会
This is nice.
真好!
Backyard.
Oh, shit.
奥，浑蛋
He always does this.
他老是这样
I'm surprised he can exist like this.
我很惊讶他居然还活到今天
How do we know he's okay?
我们怎么知道他没问题?
Well, he's not dead. Listen.
他还活着
听着
He's not dead. He's just passed out. It's a condition.
他只是昏过去，只是偶发
他可能把那女的给吓坏了
He really scared the shit out of that lady.
What causes it? Sex?
什么原因?性?
Narcolepsy doctors are saying it's brought on by certain chemical reactions in the brain.
脑中某种化学反应药物疡间症
Comes about in situations of stress.
可能是紧张导致
Some hustler, huh?
太兴奋了!
Well, where are we gonna take him?
那我们把他放在哪里?
不能把他留在这
We can't just leave him here.
Come on, Mikey.
来吧，麦可
Hey, Mike, you stay here.
麦可，你留在这
When you wake up, come back into town. I'll be waiting for you.
醒来以后，你就进城去
我会等你
You'll be safer here in this comfy neighborhood than in the city.
你留在这地方会比城里安全
我在这种地方长大
I grew up in a neighborhood like this.
跟我老爸住在一起
And my dad...
he has more fucking righteous gall...
他老以为自己比所有的人优越
than all the property and people he lords over...
and those he also created... like me, his son.
包括他的儿子，我
But I almost get sick thinking that I am a son to him.
我一想到我是他儿子就想吐
You know you have to be as good as him to keep up.
你得跟他一样的好
You have to be able to lift as big a weight.
跟他举得一样高
You have to be able to throw that weight as far...
跟他丢得一样远
or make as much money, or be as heartless.
要不然你就得听他的
My dad doesn't know that I'm just a kid.
老爸不了解我只是个孩子
He thinks I'm a threat.
他觉得我丢他的脸
No, I won't listen! I won't listen to you!
不要，我要不听他的
Hey, Scotty! Come on, you big stud!
麦考特，快来
When you wake up, wipe the slugs off your face.
当你醒来接
Get ready for a new day.
又开始新的一天
I never thought I could make it as a real model.
我从不敢想成为真的模特儿
You know, fashion-oriented modeling.
你知道，那种服装模特儿
我比较善长全身照
'Cause I'm better at full-body poses.
It's all right so long as the photographer doesn't come on to you...
那些摄影最好别想吃我豆腐
and expect something for nothing.
我是在讨生活
I'm trying to make a living. I like to have a professional attitude.
我喜欢有敬业的精神
Of course, if the guy can pay me, hell yeah.
当然如果有人付我钱
Here I am for him. I'll sell my ass.
我也当然可以出卖我的灵魂
Do it on the street occasionally for cash.
偶尔到街上赚点花钱
Or I'll be on the cover of a book.
要不然做个封面男孩呢
It's when you start doing things for free that you start to grow wings.
当你开始提供免费服务时
那就成了同性恋
Isn't that right, Mike?
对不对，麦可
- What? - Wings, Michael.
什么?
You grow wings and become a fairy.
那就成了同性恋
你担什么心
What do you care about money? Shit, you got plenty of money.
你有的是钱
Why don't you go ahead and do whatever it is that you do...
那你尽管去做你想做的
I can only imagine what that is... for free?
我想像得出那是什么
Is that right, sweetie?
是不是这样，甜心
所以多少钱才叫有钱?甜心
So, how much is a lot of money, honey?
你干甚么还做这些封面男孩呢?
What are you doing on the cover of that magazine? Slumming?
从事慈善事业?
Actually, Mikey's right. I am going to inherit money.
其实麦可说得对
我会继承我老爸的财产
A lot of money.
一大笔钱
Hi.
怎么回事
- What's happening? - Nothing.
没事
要搭便车吗?
- You want a lift? - A lift?
好吧
很好
Yes.
这不是那女士的车吗?
Isn't this that, uh... that lady's car?
- What's her name? - Alena.
她叫什么名字?
阿莲娜
- Is she a friend of yours? - No, not really.
对
她是你的朋友?
- She's a very good friend of mine. - Good.
不!我不认识她
她是我的好朋友
很好
Any friend of Alena's a good friend of mine.
阿莲娜的朋友就是我的好朋友
- You want to be my friend? - No.
你要做我的朋友吗?
不要
我叫汉斯，从德国来
My name is Hans.
I'm from Germany.
Now I live in America...
我现在住在美国，卖汽车件
- selling pieces for cars. - Mm-hmm.
- Say, why don't you get in? - No.
你上车吧!
不要
I take you wherever you want to go.
我送你到你要去的地方
你要去哪里?
- Where you want to go? - Home.
回家
上车
- Get in the car. - No.
不
This guy's a pervert. I can tell, man.
那家伙是个性变恋
你自己回家去
Why don't you go home? Go the fuck home.
波特兰
How did we get home?
我们怎么回来的?
那个德国人叫汉斯的
That German guy, Hans.
他送你到城里，你昏倒了
He brought you downtown. You were passed out.
他说要到波特兰去
He said he was heading to Portland, so I asked him for a ride.
所以我请他顺便送我们一程
我不记得一个叫汉斯的德国人
For some reason, I'm forgetting a German guy named Hans.
Well, you were sleeping.
你拿他多少钱把我给卖了
So, how much do you make off me when I'm asleep?
麦可，只是搭个车而已
Just a ride, Mike.
我没有拿他的钱
I don't make anything.
什么，你以为我出卖你的身体
What, you think I sell your body while you're asleep?
No, Mike, I'm on your side.
不会?我是你朋友
Gary's up here somewhere. He left about three days ago.
盖端也在这附近
他叁天前走了
He flew up here with a...
跟一个美容师来过
hairdresser.
不可思议!
Exotic.
我听说鲍伯会来这里
I heard something about Bob coming up here to town. Is that true?
- You hear anything about that? - Bob.
真的?你真的听说了?
Bob.
I don't know. I hope he's in town.
我不知道，我希望他在城里
- We'll have fun if Bob's in town. - Yeah, I wouldn't mind seeing him.
如果鲍伯在我们就有搞头
对，我真希望见见他
Hey, didn't you two have like a...
喂，你们俩不是，像一对
I kind of remember you having, like, this real heavy, uh...
我似乎记得你们之间有些事
什么事
- Thing? - Thing. A heavy thing goin', right?
很认真的事，对不对?
- Yeah, we had a real heavy thing going. - Huh.
对，我们之间很认真
他好像老是跟我在一起
- He was fucking in love with me. - That's what I thought.
我就知道
- Yes. - He taught me better than school did.
他教我很多事，比学校还多
I love Bob more than my father.
我爱鲍伯比爱我爸还多
I'd say I love Bob more than my mother and my father.
甚至比爱我妈和我爸还多
Yeah, I wouldn't mind seeing him. I'm... I'm hoping that he comes to town.
我们也许会见到他
我希望他到城里来
Hey, you dick!
喂，你这混蛋
Scotty, my friend.
史考特，老友
Ah, you... Hey. You like that, huh? You like that.
你喜欢吗?你喜欢
My new Nikes. My new bracelet.
新的耐吉球鞋，新手套
It says Rudy, though, but that's cool.
有够酷
My new Calvins.
What a dickhead.
So stupid.
愚蠢极了
Not when I'm eating. Don't blow it in my face.
别在我吃饭时收到我脸上
It's the smoking section.
这里是吸烟区
Um, this guy books up in a black Porsche around the corner.
那家伙开着黑色的宝时捷
Uh, I'm asking my friend if, you know, this guy's okay, if he's cool.
我问他们这个人正不正
They say... They say, "Yeah, he'll treat you really good.
他们说，他人很好
He'll, uh, you know... He'll... He'll pay you what you want.
他会对你很好
He'll, you know... He'll smoke weed with you. He'll do whatever."
你要多少钱也就付你多少
他会和你一块吸大麻
I hadn't dated before or tricked...
他什么都依你
or done anything like that before, so I went with this guy.
我从没约会过或吸毒
- Blew it off. - Well... Uh...
所以我就跟他走
把烟吹走
走，我们到公园去
"Let's go to... Let's go to the park. Let's go to Washington Park."
我们去华盛顿公国
So, I said, "Okay. That's cool. Let's go to Washington Park then."
我说好啊，很好
And, uh, all of a sudden, before I know it...
我们到华盛顿公国
I mean, I already laid down the law before I got into the car.
我那时根本不了解情况
我上车前就告诉他我的条件
I told him what I do and what I don't do.
我告诉他那些事我做那些不做
So, uh, we got up there, and he just started doing whatever he wanted.
然接我们就去了那里
My first date was in Portland. I was, um...
他就自顾自的做那件事
我的第一次是在波特兰
I was hanging out at the City Club one night.
那晚我在俱乐部闲逛
I was frying really hard on acid and speed.
克药克得正忘我之际
There was this big black guy who had a lot of eight balls...
有个大黑人有好多毒品和银子
of speed and a lot of money.
And, uh, he wanted to get his dick sucked.
他想要找我口交
And, uh, I was pretty broke, and he offered me 60 bucks...
而我那时几乎破产
and a bunch of speed.
他要付我60块钱和好多大麻
- So, I went up to his hotel... - I guess you're just gonna starve.
你不让我们帮忙你会饿死
What she's feeling sorry for herself for? What's that all about?
她何必如此难过
So, the plan was, uh... He was on the third floor.
So my buddy Scott would hang out on the street on a bench down there.
结果是他的房间在叁楼
When I got up to his room, I was gonna toss the money out the window to Scott.
我把钱从窗口丢下给史考特
There's not fucking much I could do. I was up in the... in the woods, in a thicket.
我那时不知道该怎么办
我在一堆树林里，厚厚的丛林
I couldn't get out or anything like that. I wouldn't do what he wanted me to do.
我跑不掉
根本就是强暴我
So, he just kind of flipped out all over me.
He basically raped me. He put a fuckin' wine bottle up my butt, right?
他把一个酒瓶放在我屁股上
It was, like... It was, like, horrible.
那真是可怕极了
So, we get up there in the room, and he, like, just...
所以我们走进了房间
他开始脱光衣服而且自慰
He starts getting naked and jackin' off and shit. And I start gettin' freaked out.
我突然改变主意想打退堂鼓
And I say, "No, I don't want to do this date."
我告诉他我不想做这笔生意
I say, "Let's go down to the street, and I'll get the money back from my friend Scott.
说我们到街上找朋友要回钱
And we'll just... we'll cancel it, right?"
所以我们就取消了这笔生意
So, we go down to the street to get the money back...
然接我们下楼到街上去拿回钱
可是史考特早走了
and Scott's, like, long gone, you know.
What's this? Ooh!
这是怎么回事?怎么回事?
So we're hanging out, and I'm all, "Wait. He'll be right back. Let's just wait for him."
所以我们在商场等着
等等，他马上就回来
他马上回来，我们等他一下
So, we wait about five minutes,
我们大概等了5分钟
and he starts telling me how he's gonna kick my fuckin' ass and shit.
他说他要狠狠的踢我
没有朋友能帮助我
And how my friend's gone and how he's gonna kill me and all this shit and beat me up.
他还说他要杀了我，接扁我
So I had to go upstairs and do the date anyway. And, um...
最后，我没办法只好跟他上楼
跟他完成交易
This black guy, he had a big old fucking cock and shit.
他那老二好大、好丑
And, um, it was this totally awful experience, um...
那真是一场恐怖的经验
And that was... that was my first date. I never did another one until a year later.
那就是我的初夜
以后我再也不敢再做
“直到一年以后
Jesus. The things we've seen.
老天，我们看到的那些事
Do you remember a thing since we moved from graffiti bridge?
你可记得我们搬开涂鸦桥的事
No more of that, Budd.
巴德，再也别提那事
史考特，那个肥仔来了
Hey, Scotty! Here comes that fat guy!
- He owes me money! - Who?
他还久我钱
谁
You know, the fat one, Pigeon!
你知道，就是那个胖家伙
皮经
"I think that I shall never see...
我想诗绝不如树那样的可爱
a poem as lovely as a tree."
Hey, everybody! There goes Bob, the chiseler!
那个骗子鲍伯来了
Here comes Bob, the sewer!
The thrasher!
I think my friends can see...
我想
我的朋友们看见我从波西回来
that I am back from Boise.
- And the listener! - Hey, everybody, look!
鲍伯是个倾听者
更甚
- And more than that... - Bob's back!
my real father.
我真正的父亲
- Is Jane Lightwork alive, Bob? - She's alive, Budd.
鲍伯，珍菜沃克还活着?
她还活着，巴德
- Is she holding on? - Old. Old, Budd.
她还好吗?
老了，老了，巴德
She must be old. She has no choice.
她一定老了
她没其他选择
Here comes Santa Claus!
圣诞老人来了
- Yeah! - Whoo!
老天，我们看到的那些事!
Jesus, the things we've seen.
Aren't I right, Bob? Aren't I right?
鲍伯，我说得对不对
我说得对不对?
We have heard the chimes at midnight.
我们什么事都经历过
That we have. That we have.
是啊，我们什么事都经历过
In fact, Bob, we have.
事实上，鲍伯，我们是经历过
Jesus. The things we've seen.
老天，我们看的那些事!
- Where's Bob? - Crashed out in his room.
鲍伯在哪?睡着了?
Snoring like a horse.
鼾声像猪一样
What did you get?
你找到什么?
I think this is coke. I'm not sure though.
我看是古柯硷
我不太确定
Yeah, it's fucking coke.
对，是古柯硷
Oh, fuck!
What the hell? Scott.
史考特，我的好儿子
My true son.
- How are you? What time is it? - What do you care?
你可好?
什么时候了?
你担心什么?
Why, you wouldn't even look at a clock unless hours were lines of coke...
干嘛，你从不看钟一眼
除非时针是一排排的古柯硷
dials looked like the signs of gay bars...
或钟壳像同性恋酒吧般
or time itself was a fair hustler in black leather.
不然时间不过是文明人的事
Isn't that right, Bob?
对不对，鲍伯
There's no reason to know the time. We are timeless.
没有理由要知道几点
如果你是永恒的
Aren't you forgetting, Scotty, my boy...
你忘了，史考特
the mayor's son, no less...
市长的公子
that we who steal...
那天半夜
do so at midnight?
我们偷了
Who ripped me off?
谁偷了我的东西?
巴德，巴德
Budd! Budd!
- Yes, Bob? - I fell asleep, and I've been robbed!
什么事，鲍伯
我被偷了
Jane!
You'd think I could keep the peace of my house.
珍
我能不能有个安静的夜
Jane! I know you well enough.
珍，我跟你很熟
Bob! Bob, we'll find your drugs.
鲍伯，鲍伯
我们会找到你的古柯硷
We'll find them.
我们会找到的
This hotel is full of thieves, junkies!
这旅馆里都是贼眼毒鬼
你就是那个贼
You are the thief.
你把我给坑了，史考特
You have corrupted me, Scotty.
我在认识你前有多纯洁
I was an innocent before I met you.
现在，你看我多么邪恶
And now look at me, just a little better than wicked.
- I used to be a virtuous man. - Ha!
我以前是个多么高尚的君子
Well, virtuous enough.
最少很有道德感
我极少骂人
I swore a little. I never gambled more than seven times a week! Poker!
我一礼拜不赌超过7次
I never picked up a street boy more than once a quarter.
扑克牌
我每叁个月才召一次男妓
- Of an hour! - Of an hour.
Bad company has corrupted me.
坏朋友让我堕落了
I'll be darned if I haven't forgotten what the inside of a church looks like.
真要命我忘了教堂是什么样子
I see a change for Bob to make.
我发觉鲍伯变了
从偷到传道
From stealing... to preaching.
Stealing is my vocation, Scott.
史考特，偷东西是我的职业
- It's not a sin for a man... - Hey, psst!
“个人尽总不是罪恶吧
to labor at his vocation.
Very early tomorrow morning there's gonna be a bunch...
明天一早，有个摇滚乐团
of small-time rock-and-roll promoters coming back from their gig.
他们从演唱会回来
And every night they walk home with the loot.
他们每晚带着收入走路回去
They stop by the Grotto Bar. It's about a half...
他们会在格鲁特酒吧停一下
No, it's about mile down the road from here.
大概在半哩之外
不，大约从这条路去一哩之远
Dude, if we can't steal from them going into the bar...
如果在他们进酒吧前没会抢
dude, we can get them comin' out!
那就等他们出来再干
- See, Bob, dude? - Not me.
你听说清楚没，鲍伯
So long as I don't know these guys personally, it's okay with me.
知道了
只要我不认识那些人就好办
See, uh... They're from Beaverton, new to the business.
他们从贝佛顿来的
他们是新手
I'm not gonna go along with this crackpot scheme, especially since Gary thought it up.
我可不参加这个疯狂的计划
尤其是盖端生的点子
Come off it, Mike. There is a better way to make a buck...
别这样，麦可
有别的赚钱的好办法
something to fall back on other than your ass.
这总比靠屁股赚钱好吧
I'll fall back when Scott inherits his money.
我可以靠史考特的钱
Bob, we don't need these guys. We can do this ourself. Fuck them!
鲍伯，我们不需要他加入
我们自己可以做
- Come on. I have a joke I want to play. - Okay.
浑蛋
别这样，放手
我想开个玩笑
- A joke I can't pull off alone. - Okay. I think that stuff was...
好
我一个人没办法开这玩笑
好吧
- Bob! - Oh, my sweetheart.
鲍伯
- Come and rob with us tomorrow. - I was going to anyway. I was just kidding.
好，我的甜心
明天跟我们一块去抢
我本来就要去，只是开玩笑
- Good. - Right? We'll have fun.
- All right. - We'll be rich!
很好
好了
- Yeah, we'll be rich. - We're gonna be rich.
我们要发财了!
我们快要发财了!
- Gary says we'll be rich! - We're gonna be rich!
盖端说我们快发财了
要发财了!
We're gonna be rich. We're gonna be rich.
我们要发财了!
We're gonna be rich.
Ho! Ho! Ho!
Budd? Budd. It's all right, Budd.
巴德，巴德
Budd, just... just relax, Budd.
没关系，巴德
巴德，放轻松，巴德
Provide for us, oh, great psychedelic papa!
拯救我们心灵的父亲
Scotty!
史考特
When you inherit your fortune on your 21st birthday...
离你过2l岁生日继承财产
Let's see. How far away is this?
还要多久?
One week away, Bob. Just one more week.
“个礼拜，鲍伯
只要再一个礼拜
我们别自称抢匪
Let's not call ourselves robbers but Diana's foresters...
我们是莫娜的森林
gentlemen of the shade...
夜晚的君子，月亮的宠儿
minions of the moon...
men of good government.
贤良政府的人民
When I turn 21, I don't want any more of this life.
当我2l岁时要停止这种日子
My mother and father will be surprised at the incredible change.
我的父母会惊讶我惊人的改变
It will impress them more when such a fuckup like me turns good...
他们会对我的自新另眼相看
than if I had been a good son all along.
我会成为他们的好儿子
All my bad behavior I will throw away to pay a debt.
改变以前不好的行为以补偿
我会在大家对我失望时改过
I will change when everybody expects it the least.
You'll become a head-roller... a hatchet man for your old man.
你会成为杀人凶手
你老爸的亲手
No!
不会的!
鲍伯，你才会变成亲手
You will be the hatchet man, Bob!
That will be your job.
我会给你这份工作
And so there will rarely be a job hatcheted.
然接你会整天游手好闻
It will all be just one endless party.
而有开不完的宴会
对不对?
Won't it?
But at least my little friend has offered me a job.
至少我的小朋友给我一份工作
They're so good to me.
他们对我真好
How long has it been, Bob, since you could see your dick?
鲍伯，你从什么时候变这么胖
About four years, Scotty.
大概有4年了，史考特
Four years of grief blows a man up like a balloon.
悲哀的4年!
把一个人吹得像汽球
- There's rock-and-roll money coming this way! - And they're drunk as skunks!
有一大笔钱正朝着我们来
他们烂醉如泥
All right. All right. You four should head them off there.
好，好
你们四个把他们截断
We four? How many are walking with 'em?
我们四个?
对，你们四个
他们有五个
- There's five of 'em. - Five? Shouldn't they be robbing us?
五个?
他们该不会倒过来抢我们吧!
All right. If they escape from you guys, Mike and I will get 'em here.
好吧，如果他们逃掉了
麦可和我会在这里挡住
Oh, eight feet of this muck's like 30 yards of flat road...
奥，走进了泥路了
Would you guys shut up? Shut up! Pay attention.
大概有3o码长
闭嘴!
蹲下!
- Squat down! Squat down! - Squat down? You got a crane to lift me up?
有没有起重把我吊走?
- Where are our disguises? - Right behind us.
我们的行头在那?
就在接面
- Let's go. - Okay.
好
- Who are these jokers, man? - Look like Rajneesh.
这些小丑是谁啊?
像印度巫师
This one looks like he's a little thirsty.
他看来有点涡
靠墙站好，笨瓜
Up against the wall, you sully scumbags!
Don't shoot.
别开枪
- Up against the wall. - Come on! Come on!
靠墙站好
- Don't shoot us. - That's right.
- Fags. - Okay, set the box down. That's right.
把箱子放下
Thank you. Nice and gently. Nice and gently.
谢了
好好的，慢慢的
Let's see what we have.
看看有些什么玩意
Yes, my baby doll. Ooh.
太好了，我的宝贝
Tickets, anyone, for next week's show?
每人一张下礼拜演唱会入场奏
Scott and Mike have disappeared.
史考特和麦可不见人影
Could the shots have scared them away?
大概枪声把他们给吓跑了
Maybe we should get the hell out of here.
我们快点溜之大吉
Are they such chickens?
这些贼都四处逃官
Let's get the hell out of here!
The thieves scatter!
有如惊弓之乌
Bob Pigeon will sweat to death.
Has anyone seen my son?
谁看到我儿子没?
It's been a full three months since I last saw him.
我叁个月前看过他
我儿子史考特在哪?
Where is my son Scott?
- We don't know, sir. - Ask around in old town.
我们不清楚，先生
到老城去打听打听
Some of the taverns there.
问问那些酒的人
Some say he frequently is seen down there drinking with street denizens.
有人说他常和流浪汉在那喝酒
Some who they say even rob our citizens and store owners.
更有人说抢劫商店和民家
I can't believe that such an effeminate boy supports such friends.
他如此柔弱怎么变这些朋友
喂，麦可
Hey, Mikey, how long have I been here on the streets on this crusade?
我在街上流浪有多久了?
我叁年半前回到城里来认识你
Huh. W-Well, I came back to town around three and a half years ago...
and that's when I met you.
所以，已经有
已经有叁年了，麦可
- So, it's been... - It's been three years, Mike.
Yeah, almost four years. That's a long time.
是啊，快四年了
好长的一段日子
What I'm getting at, Mike, is that we're still alive.
麦可，我的意思是
我们居然还活着
对，很明显的，是不是?
Yeah. Well, that's obvious, isn't it?
是啊!太明显了
Yeah. It's incredibly obvious.
如果有人炸掉这个城
They could drop a big old bomb on this city. Know what we would do?
你想我们会怎么做?
Take shelter?
躲起来
麦可，这摩托车偷得太容易
- This bike was caught with much ease, Mike. - Yes.
是啊
And the reward for the joke that we played last night...
我们昨晚开的玩笑的奖赏
will be the unbelievably huge lies that Bob will come up with now.
将换来鲍伯一大串的谎言
弱者的奖牌
A plague on all cowards!
怎么了，鲍伯
What's up, Bob? Where have you been?
你到哪里去了?
Where have I been?
你的男子汉气概呢?
If manhood's not forgotten on the face of the earth, then I'm a shot herring.
坐下，小浑蛋
You sit down, you little fuck.
A mayor's son.
公子哥儿，你过来
如果我教你如何成为男子汉
If I jog you out of that right and teach you to be a man...
你父亲将会以你为荣
your father would be as proud of me as he would you, Scotty!
史考特
Why, you whoring round man.
胖子，你胡扯什么?
What is the matter?
到底怎么回事?
你们是不是个弱者?
Are you not a coward? Answer that.
你们两个，回答我
- And that goes double. - You calling me a coward? You fat duck.
你叫我弱者，你这肥鸭
I'd give a thousand dollars to be able to run as fast as you can.
我赌一千块跑得比你快
- It'll never happen, Bob. - Where's the money, Bob?
这事绝不可能发生，鲍伯
钱呢?鲍伯
在哪?
Where is it?
被二、叁十个庞克给抢走了
- Taken from us by 20 or 30 punks. - Thirty?
I was struggling with a dozen of them.
我一人跟他们一打人打起来
I think my arm's broken from the fight.
我的手臂都打断了
Certainly a toe. Most definitely a rib.
大概脚指头也，断了
肋骨一定也断了
让我来说你们听
- Let me tell you about it. - Tell us about it, please.
说给我们听
请吧
我们四个攻击他们一打人
- We four set upon a dozen of 'em. - Sixteen, at least, Digger, my boy.
最少有l6个
老天，大概更多
Yeah, and got their money. As we were splitting it, 16 others set upon us.
对，拿了钱，正当我们分钱
另外有l6个家伙攻击我们
Thank God you had not murdered some of them.
但愿你没杀了他们
谋杀?
Murdered? Well, they are past praying for.
他们死定了
我杀了两个家伙
I peppered two of them.
两个穿皮夹克的庞克
- Two punks in leather jackets. - What?
什么?
- I'll tell you, son. These four came in close. - You said there were two...
我告诉你儿子，有四个欺近我
你本来说有两个，现在四个
Four! I said there were four, Scott.
我说原来有四个，史考特
Four.
四个
These four came from the front, kicking at me, pulling their knives.
那四个人走到我前面踢我
阻止他们的刀
我挥着我的刀，对付他们七个
And I whipped out the blade and took all seven as a target, like this!
就像这样
Seven! Just a second ago, there were four.
七个?
才一会前，你说有四个
- In leather? - No, Bob, my friend.
穿皮衣的?
不，鲍伯，我的朋友
There was four of 'em, and they all had leather on.
他们有四个人都穿着皮夹克
我算有七个
Seven, by my count.
让他说
Leave him alone. We shall have more soon.
马上会有更多
As I was saying, these nine in the alleyway that I told you about...
我刚说有九个在巷道里
There's more already, I see. Nine?
你看又多了几个
他们全副武装共有l1个人
Full force, and with thought, seven of the 11 I pegged!
我杀了七个
There are 11 now. He started with two.
现在成了十一个人
But, as the devil would have it, three of them came at my back.
他开始说二个人
更糟糕的事情是
两个人在我背接，穿绿色的
They were wearing green.
他们跟我打成一团
And they had it out with me.
Because it was so dark, Scotty...
史考特
那时伸手不见五指
that you could not see your hand.
如果那时黑得伸手不见五指
How could you see green when it was so dark...
你又如何看得出是绿色?
that you couldn't see your hand?
- Tell us the reason. Come on, Bob. - Tell us!
告诉我们真象吧!
快啊，鲍伯
- Come on, Bob! - Tell us the reason, Bob!
快告诉我们
快告诉我们真象，鲍伯
- Tell us why. - You can tell 'em. Go on and tell 'em.
告诉我们为什么
说啊，告诉他们
如果不是被迫
- Upon compulsion? - Come on, Bob.
我才不会告诉你
Not for you or I or all the rest of the world would I tell you...
on compulsion!
I will no longer be guilty of this sin!
我将不会再有罪
This sanguine coward, this horseback-breaker...
你这个弱者
庞大拥肿的肥猪
this huge hill of jelly!
Punk! You starfish!
伪装者，我要揭毁你的骗局
Oh, for breath to utter what lies of a tailor's yardstick!
微不足道的小角色
You boot case! You vile punk!
卑鄙的庞克
Breathe a while, and then do it again.
喘口气再继续等
But hear me out.
听我道来
We two saw you four set upon five.
我们俩看到你们四个
攻击那五个人
And, Bob...
而你拨腿就溜
you carried yourself away at the slightest noise.
And roared for mercy. And ran and roared as ever I heard a bull calf.
边跑还边叫救命
你还有什么话说
What trick, what device can you find...
看你如何掩饰这害人的事
to hide from this open and apparent shame?
Yes.
看你如何掩饰这害人的事
What new trick do you have for us now, Bob?
鲍伯，你还有什么新把戏
Good Lord, lads.
我太清楚你了
I know you as well as he that made you.
你想我会杀了你这继承人
Do you think that I would kill the heir apparent?
Do you think I would turn on you, Scotty?
你想我会跟你作对
你是我们唯一的希望
Why, you're our only ticket out of this poverty and oppression.
我比希腊大力士还要强壮
I am as valued as Hercules.
But beware my instinct.
但请你了解我的本能
The lion will not touch the true heir.
虎毒不食子
Good Lord, lads...
幸好钱在你那
I'm glad you have the money.
如果要找一个胖男人
If we're looking for a fat man, why don't we get one under the bridge?
我们到桥下找一个不就结了
警长跟警卫队来了
Oh! Oh! The sheriff and his posse are here.
史考特
他们要来搜查这里
Scotty, they've come to search the house. Shall I let them in?
要不要让他们进来
警察来了!
Call in the sheriff!
老天，这是什么味道
- God. - Oh, God, what's that smell?
- Hey! Hey! - There they are.
那边，那边
- Over there! Over there! - Come here, you little shit!
Come here!
There he goes! In the door!
门里面
Baby, yeah.
Wait, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait!
Aha! What have we here?
什么事?
Pardon me, Mr. Favor. An informant has followed certain men into this house.
对不起，费优先生
有人密告某些嫌犯在这里
- What men? - One of them is well known, sir.
什么人?
先生，其中有一人小有名气
- A large fat man. - Fat as butter.
“个块头很大的胖男人
肥的像牛油一般
他不在这
Well, he's not here.
不过如果我看到他
But if I see him...
我答应
I'll promise you that I'll send him to you by...
明天晚餐把他送给你
dinnertime tomorrow...
去接受你的控诉
to answer against any such charges.
So, would you leave us alone?
这样，你可以请走了吗?
- You! - Sorry for the interruption.
抱歉打断你们
We have a message for you from your father.
你父亲要我们带口信给你
He'd like to see you as soon as possible.
他想尽快看看你
去你的
Fuck you.
I don't know whether it is God trying to get back at me...
难道是老天故意在惩罚我
for something I have done, but...
your passing through life makes me certain that you are marked...
你这样虚渡青春，浪费生命
and that heaven is punishing me for my mistreatings.
老天爷在惩罚我过去做的错事
When I got back from France and set foot in Clark County...
我从法国回来在克拉克郡落脚
and saw what your cousin, Bill Davis, had done at his family's ranch...
看到你表弟比尔戴维斯的农场
I thought, by my soul...
他比你还有心继承我的事业
he has more worthy interest to my estate than you could hold a candle to.
And being no older than you are, he organizes operations for state senators...
他年纪比你还小
替参议员工作，为生意人游说
lobbies for the small businessman...
and has an ambitious five-year plan for the forest that even I would like to support.
他有个拯救森林的五年计划
看他的决心连我都想支持他
And then I have to think of you...
然接我不得不想到你
你是何等的颓废
and what a degenerate you are.
Don't think that, Father.
别这样想，父亲
你会发现这不是真的
You will find out it's not true.
And I hope that somebody forgives the people...
我会原谅那些说我坏话的人
that have swayed your fond thoughts away from me.
For a time will come when I will make this northern youth...
时间到我会完全改过
trade me his good deeds for my indignities.
变成跟他一样的好孩子
比尔戴维斯是我的好表弟
Bill Davis is my good cousin.
But even the slightest worship of his time...
我不认为你该如此看重他
Dad...
I will die...
我将誓死赢回你对我的爱
a hundred thousand deaths...
before that happens.
I wanna see my face on the front of album covers.
我要有自己的唱片
I wanna produce my own music.
我要自己作曲
You know, I just... I just want total control over my music.
完全控制我的音乐
I wanna engineer it. I wanna mix it.
我要亲自录音
You know, I wanna... I wanna get my own say on opening bands.
我要控制我自己的乐团
Then I'd like to, like, stand in back of bigger pictures of myself.
我要成为有名的音乐创作者
- That's good. - And you?
那真好
那你呢?
I don't care.
我不在乎
我们去那里
Where should we go?
- To visit my brother. - You have a brother?
我们去找我哥哥
你有哥哥?
Yeah, I've got a brother, man. You know that.
是啊，我有个哥哥
Where is he?
他在哪?
Well, I'm thinking he should be someplace in, uh, the potato state.
应该在马铃着州
Idaho.
爱达荷
Shut up, Mike.
麦可，住嘴
If I'd known it'd be this hard to start, I wouldn't have stopped it at all.
早知道这么难发动我就不熄火
I've been on this road before.
我以前来过这条路
This is my road.
这条路是届放我的
Looks like a fucked-up face.
像张破碎的脸
Like it's saying, "Have a nice day" or something.
它似乎在说美好的一天或什么
你懂我的意思吗?
See what I mean, Scott?
Scott, look.
史考特，看
Thanks.
谢了
What?
什么?
- You need some help with this, man? - Shut up.
嘿老兄，需要帮忙吗?
闭嘴
You shut up.
你闭嘴
- You suck. - Do you know anything about bikes?
你惶不惶摩托车
Yeah, I-I've turned over a few.
我发动过几次
Scott, man, where are you going?
你去哪里?
能抛开一切感觉真好
Getting away from everything feels good.
Yeah, it does.
是啊，真好
When I left home, the maid asked me where I was off to.
我离家时，女问我去哪里?
I said, "Wherever, whatever.
我说无论何处，无论什么
Have a nice day."
You had a maid?
你有女?
Yeah.
对
If I had a normal family and a good upbringing...
如果我有正常的家庭好的教养
那我会是个人格正常的人
then I would have been a well-adjusted person.
Depends on what you call normal.
那要看你叫什么是正常
Yeah, it does.
是啊
Well, you know, normal, like... like a mom and a dad...
可是，你知道正常
就像一个人有个亲和母亲
and a dog and shit like that.
一只狗
Normal. Normal.
正常，正常
So you didn't have a normal dog?
所以你以前没有一只正常的狗
- No, I didn't have a dog. - You didn't have a... a normal dad?
没有，我根本没有狗
Didn't have a dog or... or... or a normal dad anyway.
你没有正常的父亲?
没有狗，也没有正常的父亲
That's all right. I don't feel sorry for myself.
没关系
我并不为自己感到难过
I mean, I feel like I'm... I feel like I'm, you know, well-adjusted.
我是说我觉得我人格很正常
What's a normal dad?
什么叫正常的老爸?
I don't know.
我不知道
I'd like to talk with you.
我想要跟你谈谈
I mean, I'd like to really talk with you.
我意思是我想真的跟你谈谈
We're talking right now, but, you know...
我们现在正在谈啊
I don't know. I... I don't feel like I can be...
可是，你知道我不觉得我
I don't feel like I can be close to you.
我不觉得我们接近
I mean, we're close.
我是说我们很接近
Right now we're close, but, I mean... You know...
现在我们很接近但你知道
How close? I mean...
要多接近?
I don't know. Whatever.
我不知道，管他的?
What?
什么?
What do I mean to you?
我，我对你有什么意义?
What do you mean to me?
你对我有什么意义?
Mike, you're my best friend.
麦可，你是我最好的朋友
I know, man. And I... I know... I know I'm your friend.
我知道我是你的朋友
We're good friends. And it's good to be, you know, good friends.
我们是好朋友
That's a good thing.
能成为好朋友很好
这是好事
So?
所以呢?
So, I just...
所以 我是
That's okay.
没什么
We can be friends.
我们可以做朋友
I only have sex with a guy for money.
我为了钱才跟男人作爱
Yeah, I know.
我知道
And two guys can't love each other.
两个男人无法相爱
Yeah.
Well, I... I don't know. I mean...
这我不清楚
I mean, for me...
我是说对我而言
I could love someone even if I...
我可以爱一个人
you know, wasn't paid for it.
即使不是为钱
I love you and...
我爱你
you don't pay me.
而你不用付我钱
- Mike. - I really want to kiss you, man.
麦可
我很想吻你
Good night, man.
晚安
I love you though.
我爱你
You know that.
你知道的
I do love you.
我真的爱你
All right. Come here, Mike.
好吧，过来这，麦可
It's just like... Come on.
这简直是算了，睡觉了
Just go to sleep. Come on.
Oh, shit!
奥，混蛋，完了
Oh, shit! Oh, man!
Looks like this is it.
奥，混蛋，完了
我们完了
Can't get the bike started. Cops are coming. Stuck in the middle of nowhere.
发动不起来了
警察来了
- Yeah? - With a stolen bike. Yeah, Mike.
我们又被困在这
在这荒郊野外
跟这偷来的车
Looks like this is the end.
就是啊麦可，看来我们完了
- Matter with your friend? - I don't know.
你的朋友怎么了?
I guess he doesn't like cops.
我也不清楚
- Oh, yeah? - That's how it looks.
我想他大概不喜欢警察吧
奥，是吗?
看起来如此
What are you guys doing out here?
你们在这干嘛?
这车很难发动
This cycle is one bitch to turn over, man.
But I guess you don't know anything about motorcycles, huh?
我想你大慨不会发动摩托车
- You're not a motorcycle cop. - I've turned over a few.
你不是个摩托车警察
我曾发动过几辆
Wake up, Mikey. The heat's off.
醒醒，麦可
警察已经走了
Look, Mike, sandwiches.
看，麦可，叁文治
Thanks, man.
谢了，老兄
Did I ever show you this picture of you and Mom?
你看过这张你和妈的照片没
That was taken out by the institution.
那是在精神病院外照的
We used to go out to that place on the weekends to see 'em.
我们在周末时去看她
You were about one year old at the time, I think.
我想你那时大约一岁
I hated that fucking place.
我恨那个鬼地方
Scott, how do you have a kid this young in an institution?
你怎能把婴儿放在精神病院里
- W-What does that mean? - Why were you in an institution?
我是说那是什么意思?
- Is that what you're askin' me? - I'm asking you.
你为什么会在那地方?
你是问这个吗?
我在问你
Because of Mom. They didn't think she was safe.
因为妈?
他们不觉得她很正常
但我们仍然是一家人
But we were still a family.
Me, you...
我、你和妈
and Mom.
- Where you going? - Pisser.
你上哪去?
洗手间
Don't give me any of your shit. Don't give me any of your shit!
- Dick! Dick! - I don't wanna hear any of your shit!
别再跟我胡扯
我不想再你胡说八道
- Dick! Dick! - Don't talk to me like that!
别这样跟我说话
Dick!
He's all right. This happens every time we get together.
他说的对
我每次在一块就这样
You want a drink? This?
要不要来一杯?
好
You like those? I paint 'em for a livin'.
你喜欢吗?
我画画赚点钱
Sometimes when they're finished, the people don't send me the check, so I keep 'em.
有时我画完后这些人不付钱
所以我就留着它们?
I kinda like them hangin' around. They keep me company.
我喜欢把它们挂着
他们跟我作伴
Run free and sure
No man can take
This land from them
I want you to know the truth about your mother.
我要让你知道关于你妈的真象
I know the truth about my mother.
我早知道了
I mean the real truth.
我是说真的事实
- I know. - You don't know.
我知道了
You wanna go around through life believing the lies?
你不知道
难道你一生都相信那谎言
这是你要的吗?
Is that what you want?
Listen to me when I'm talking to you.
听我说，我在跟你说话
You know, she used to go out at night and look for men when I was asleep.
你知道她常在晚上出去
趁我睡觉去找别的男人
She'd go out to different bars, you know.
她逛好几个酒吧
She'd shake her ass at anybody that was interested.
向对她有意恩的男人摇着屁股
That's how she met that guy from Reno...
她就是那样勾上那个家伙
that low-life, gamblin' cowboy fuck.
那个下流的赌鬼牛仔
He worked at one of those big casinos in Vegas.
他在拉斯维加斯的大赌场上班
He got fired for fuckin' with the cards.
他作牌被炒续鱼
He was a real scumbag.
他根本是个无赖
But your mother loved him.
可是你妈爱上他，她爱上了他
She loved him.
She had it in her head that she wanted to marry this guy...
她满脑子都是他
and go off with him and... and have a little family...
她要跟他结婚，跟他走
然接组个家庭
with the house and the... the white picket fence...
有着白色墙的房子和狗
and the dog and the fuckin' station wagon.
All that shit.
还有那鬼旅行车
But he didn't want to marry her.
可是他不要跟她结婚
He didn't love her.
他并不爱她
That's around the time that you were born.
你那时正好出生
Now, she had a gun. She used to have this gun.
她有把枪，她一直有这把枪
It was a... a Smith & Wesson .38 revolver.
那是把史密斯卫森38发
And she loved this gun. She loved this gun. She used to sleep with it.
她爱这把枪
她睡觉都带着
She used to stir-fry the vegetables with the loaded gun.
她常用上膛的枪来炒青菜
I remember, I used to say, "Sharon, what're you doin'?
我记得我常说：雪伦，你干嘛
You stir-frying vegetables with the gun?
你用枪炒青菜?
You're gonna blow a hole through the frying pan."
你会把炒菜锅轰个洞
So, one night she goes to the drive-in movie...
那晚她和那牛仔去看汽车电影
with this cowboy fuck.
Jesus Christ. What... What the fuck was the name of that movie now?
老天爷，那电影叫什么来着
- It was a western. - Rio Bravo?
是部西部片
Right, Rio Bravo. It was a John Wayne movie.
叫里约布伍
是部约翰伟恩演的电影
During the movie...
电影演一半，她拿出枪
she takes this gun, sticks it in his mouth...
and blows his brains out.
插进他嘴里，轰得他脑袋开花
Rio Bravo on the big screen.
里约布活在大银幕上
John Wayne on his horse ridin' through the desert.
约翰伟恩骑着马走过沙摸
Spilled popcorn all over the front seat soakin' up the blood.
爆米花  满了前座
把血都吸乾了
Oh, come on, man. How corny.
奥，算了，少来
This is why she had to leave.
所以她得离开这里
And that guy...
那个家伙
That guy is your real father.
那家伙就是你爸
Don't fuck me in the head anymore, man!
老兄，你少骗我
I know the fucking truth! I know who my fucking real dad is!
我知道真相是什么
Who is it? Who?
我知道谁是我真正父亲
- Who? - Dick, you!
谁，谁是，谁
就是你
Richard, you're my dad. I know that.
理查，你是我爸爸，我知道
You know too much.
你知道太多了
She doesn't want to see me like this, man.
I got this from her, I don't know, a few months ago.
我几个月前收到明信片
Fuckin' got blood all over it. Did you cut your hand?
都是血，割破手了?真是的
Stupid.
亲爱的，我找到一份工作
"Dear honey, found a job in the lounge of the Family Tree in Snake River.
在蛇溪的家庭树旅台
If you're ever out this way, look me up. Love, Mom."
如果你顺路，来看看我
"Rooms, phones, color TV.
当你的妈妈
房间有电话，彩色电视
Wall-to-wall carpeting, and efficiently controlled electric heat...
地布，独立空调暖气，卫浴
combination tub and showers, game table...
游戏桌，两张椅子
And two reading chairs, with some connecting rooms."
It sounds so nice. I wouldn't mind living here.
看起来不错，我也想住在那
I'm gonna look her up, man.
我要去找她
Sharon. Sharon.
雪伦?雪伦?
There was a Sharon who worked here about a year ago, but she split.
“年前有个雪伦的在这工作
但她走了
Saved up all her money and headed for Italy.
她为了钱到意大利了
去了意大利7
- To Italy? - Yeah, Italy.
对，意大利7
Took her forever to save any cash...
花了她很长的时间为钱
but, uh, she finally did it and flew away.
她终放存够然接飞去了
她说有去找她家人
Said she was lookin' for her family. Guess she was Italian.
猜她大概是意大利人
She didn't look Italian though. She, uh, left us this address.
但她不像意大利人
她留给我们这个地址
Sharon Waters, Via Casoli, Settevene...
雪伦卫得
卡索街．西他维纳
罗马
R-Rome... Roma? Rome. She's in Rome, Italy.
她在意大利的罗马
那家伙在哪里
- There's that guy. - What guy?
哪个家伙?
那个送我们去波特兰的
Guy who gave us a ride from Portland.
他叫什么名字?
- Oh, yeah. What's his name? - What's he doing here?
他来这干嘛?
- I don't know. Is his name Hans? Hans? - Hans.
我不知道
他叫汉斯
That's it as usual. Thank you very much.
跟往常一样，谢谢
史考特
Scott. Mike.
麦可!
很高兴遇上你们
- Hey. - How nice to run into you boys.
近来可好?
- How have you been? - Gut.
很好
待会见
See you later.
407.
麦可
Mike?
干什么?
- What? - I'm extremely excited.
我非常的兴奋
我刚进来，请你等一下
I just got in. Could you please wait your turn?
可是你要不要吃点东西，麦可
But don't you want anything to eat, Mike?
我们在房间用餐
- We are ordering room service, yes? - Room service?
房间用餐?
对
Yeah. Uh, four orders of large french fries...
四份大吕薯条，很脆的
extra crispy, and some Coke.
还有些可乐，这样就够了
And that's all.
你要四份大薯条，非常脆
That makes four portion of french fries...
和一份大可乐
very crispy, and a large Coke.
对不对，麦可
- Is that correct now, Mike? - Ja. Ja. Ja.
对，对，对
多谢你，麦可
Thank you very much, Mike. Thank you.
谢谢你
- Thank you. - See you soon.
待会见
什么?
- What? - See you soon.
待会见
对，好
Yeah, right.
我让你们看这样东西
I must show you something.
我母亲
My mother.
上帝保佑她
Heaven bless her soul. She died seven years ago.
她七年前去逝了
她很美
She's very beautiful.
我也有同感
I think so.
你要看吗?
You want to see it?
她长得真像你
She looks just like you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们有些什么?
Well, what do we have?
你知道我在卖汽车件前
You know, before I was selling pieces...
for cars...
我是个表演家
I was a performer.
我有段很精彩的日子
Great time I had, being on many stages...
活跃在全世界的舞台上
Put it on.
放来听听
- Yes? You like it? Okay. - Yeah.
你要听?
我们挪出一些地方
Let's make some room.
“点灯光和音乐
Put out the light.
Turn on the music.
- Oh, sitting on a bullet - Oh, sitting on a bullet
Thinking of power
Every hour
Whoo!
Being in space
Controlling the world
With a different face
Face, face, face
Berlin
New York, Moscow
Tokyo
Well...
非常谢谢你
Thank you very much. Long time ago.
很久以前
Well, tell me something.
告诉我你们怎么来到爱达荷
How did you boys get so far? To Idaho?
我几天前在波特兰放下你们
I only left you in Portland a couple of days ago, right?
我们骑一辆可靠的摩托车
We rode on our trusty motorcycle.
你们怎么会来到达旅台呢?
And what brings you to this exciting Family Tree Inn?
生意
- Business. - Business?
生意?
Business.
什么样的生意?
What kind of business?
我们卖摩托车
- We're selling motorcycles. - Okay.
好，那让我们来
Let's go down, us...
谈谈一些生意
for some... business, right?
对不对?
Hello.
你知道我为什么要你停车
You know why I stopped you?
骑太快了
You was going too fast for this road.
如果骑太快了我就要给你罚单
For going too fast on this road, I'm gonna give you a ticket.
超速罚单
A speeding ticket.
你喜欢你的摩托车?
- You like your bike? - Mm-hmm.
那我还是得开你罚单
Well, I'm still gonna give you a ticket.
叫什么名字?
What's your name?
汉斯
- Hans. - Hans?
汉斯?
- Kline. - Kline?
克来恩
克来恩?
K-L-I...
有没有行李?
Do you have any baggage?
Hans.
汉斯
- Enjoy your flight. - Thanks.
旅途愉快
罗马
Mike! Mike, over here!
麦克，麦克，在这
他们说什么?
So, what did they want?
我请他们看着你我去叫计程车
I told them to take care of you while I got a taxi.
妈?
Mom?
Scusa.
对不起
Hi.
这是你家吗?
Is this your house?
什么
- What? - Um...
la tua casa?
这是你家?
不是，是我叔叔的家
No, this is my uncle's house...
但他现在不在家
but he's not here now.
Oh.
我是史考特
My name is Scott.
史考特
Scott.
- My name is Carmella. - How do you do?
我叫卡蜜拉
你好?
Um, how do you do?
I... Good.
我好?
Mom?
妈?
An American woman?
“个美国女人
Yeah. Do you know her?
对，你认识她?
Yeah.
Um, but is not... is not true that she lives here.
认识，她现在不住这了
不住这了
- It isn't true? - No, she...
不，她很久前就走了
She left a long time ago.
回美国去了
Back to America.
Oh, shit.
Was she your friend?
她是你朋友?
Yeah. She lived here, and...
对，她以前住这里
因为我想学英文，她就教我
'cause I wanted to learn English...
she... she... she taught... she taught it to me.
Oh. Well...
奥，你学得很好
your English is very good.
奥，这是我朋友
Oh, this is my friend.
他是麦可
- This is Mike. - Mike.
麦可?
麦可
- Mike? - Michael.
卡蜜拉
- Hi. - Carmella.
- Hi. - She knows your mom.
她认识你妈妈
真的，在哪?
Really? Where?
不，她已经
No, she...
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
啊，麦可
- Uh, Mike? - Mom!
妈
我妈的家是蓝色的
My mom's house was blue.
不，是绿色
No, it was green.
是绿色的
It was green.
我怎能忘记
How could I forget that?
Da-da, da-da-da, da-dum
Da-dum, da-da-da, da-da-da
谢谢跟我来，我想走了
Thanks for comin' all this way, though, man.
I'm ready to leave whenever you are.
What?
Grande.
- Tanta fame? - Yeah.
- Tanta fame? - "Tanta" what?
- Tanta fame? - Oh, yeah.
- You know what "fame" is? - Hungry.
你知道什愿意思?
饿了
- Hungry. Hungry. - Hungry.
Sorry.
Bacio. Bacio.
- "Bacio"? - Bacio.
This is bacio.
Yeah?
What is it?
怎么回事
It's nothing.
没事
No? Okay.
- Come on. - No. Stay, please.
请留下，这里面有栗子
- All right. - Look.
There is a castagna here inside.
- "La castagna"? - Castagna.
Castagna.
La castagna.
Know what it's for?
做什么用?
Eh, if... If they were bigger, you could eat.
长大一点可以吃
If they're bigger.
大点，我惶了
I understand.
你惶了?
- Do you? - Yes.
对，我了解你的感受
I know how you feel.
I think I fall in love.
我想我恋爱了
我想我得离开你一阵子
I'm gonna take a little time off.
你知道
You know...
也许那天我们会再碰面
maybe I'll run into you down the road.
这些钱是卖掉摩托车你的份
There's some cash. That's your share from the bike.
我恋爱了，麦可
I fell in love, Mike.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很抱欺你没找到你妈
I'm really sorry we didn't find your mom.
Scott.
史考特
What?
- Tuo fisico. - "Tuo fisico"?
Bravo, così.
Signore. Signore.
Wake up. We are in the Portland Airport.
先生，醒醒，到波特兰机场了
We're here. Whoa.
Whoa.
Please extinguish cigarettes. Thank you.
Oh, man. Where were you?
Forty D's?
So, how's your wife?
You're not very talkative tonight, man. That's cool.
Where we goin'?
That should just about do it. Man alive, there's nothing better...
than a hamburger grilled to perfection.
Cool, man.
Your burgers are getting cold, g... Holy Moly!
Bob!
Hey, Bob.
¿Qué pasa, man? I bring great tidings and much joy.
George, what blew you in?
Remember that rotgut shit we used to drink on the streets... the wino wine?
Well, I got three jugs hidden in a bush on 82nd.
We're talkin' hard-core fun, man.
All we need to do is put a ride together to the bush...
我们可有乐子，老兄
只要搭个便车到那
and we're in business.
I'm afraid if I shared your wine...
我们就可以畅饮了
I might catch this awful disease you appear to have.
我怕喝你的酒会传染上你的病
My jacket would grow little zippers all over it...
and my toes would have jingle bells on them like those there.
我的夹克会长出拉链
脚趾头会有铃铃
Bob, chill out.
Is it true that you're the greatest man on the street, that you own the street?
鲍伯，放轻松
你是不是这街上的大人物?
That is correct.
这条街是你的?
Well, then you can get us a ride to see God. Do it.
完全正确
那你可以找个便车去见上帝
If it isn't Scotty Favor himself.
去找啊
那该不是史考特费佛
Dressed in a three-piece suit, looking every bit a gentleman!
穿着叁件式西装
看起来真像个绅士
- Who, man? - Scott Favor.
谁啊?老兄
史考特费佛
He's run headlong into his inheritance.
他继承了他老头的遗产
George, Budd...
乔治、巴德、麦可
Mike.
We have waited for this day to come.
我们终放等到达一天
Scotty, I haven't seen you in a dog's age.
史考特，好久不见了
You're lookin' well. So grown up.
你看起来好极了，你长大了
Scotty, I'd like you to meet Tiger Warren.
史考特，来见见泰格军伦
He's with Muchísimo Más restaurants.
他开一家马其莫鼠餐厅
- Tiger, Scotty Favor. - Jack Favor's son?
泰格．史考特费佛
Hello, I'm pleased to meet you. Awfully sorry about your father.
杰克费佛的公子?
It's really all right. The, uh, family is taking it very hard...
你好，很荣幸见到你
关于你父亲的死我非常难过
都已经过去了，家人都很悲伤
but we live on with his memory.
但我们会永远的想念他
Scott, you ever considered a political career?
史考特，你考虑过从政治没
Come, George. Watch this.
来，乔治，看我的
You'll see the reception that I get.
看看他们对我的招待
Hey, you guys, look at this.
我们可真引人注目
It's true, we're drawing attention to ourselves, but...
Scotty will witness that I'm dying to see him...
但考特会证明我太想见他
and it won't matter how we're dressed.
所以我们穿什么就不重要
God save you! God save you, my sweet boy.
上帝保佑你，上帝保佑你
我的乖孩子
Scotty, my own true friend!
史考特，我真正的朋友
I mean you, Scotty. It's me, Bob!
我说你，史考特
是我啊!鲍伯
I don't know you, old man.
我不认识你，老头子
Please leave me alone.
请你别来打扰我
When I was young and you were my street tutor...
我年少时你教了我一些坏行为
an instigator for my bad behavior, I was planning a change.
我计划改变自己
There was a time when I had the need to learn from you...
我曾有段时间向你学习
my former and psychedelic teacher.
我前任心灵的导师
And although I love you more dearly than my dead father...
虽然我爱你胜过我死去的父亲
I have to turn away.
我还是必须离开你
Now that I have, and until I change back...
现在我已经改过
don't come near me.
别再接近我
O-U-T. Out.
出去
God.
上帝。
G-God!
上－上帝！
God?
上帝？
Pigeon.
傻瓜。
Scott Favor broke his heart.
史考特费佛伤了他的心。
肯定很安静。
Sure is quiet.
He's either in heaven or hell now.
现在，他不是在天堂，就是在地狱。
Be sure it isn't to hell.
肯定不是地狱。
He's tried to be an honest sort.
他尝试做一个诚实的人。
I'm the one who heard him cry out last night.
是我昨夜听到了他大声呼喊。
He said, "God, God, God"...
他说，“上帝，上帝，上帝...”
three or four times.
3到4次。
And when I got there, I put my hand into the bed and felt his feet.
等我到那儿，我手伸到了床，摸到了他的脚。
And they were cold as stones.
冷若石头。
And I checked the rest of his body...
我又检查了身体的其他部位...
and it, too, was as cold as stone.
也冷若石头。
In the name of the Father, and of the Son...
以圣父，圣子，圣灵之名，阿门。
and of the Holy Ghost, amen.
"'I am the resurrection and the life,' sayeth the Lord.
"I am the resurrection and the life, sayeth the lord.
'He that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.
"He that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.
And whoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.'
"And whoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die.
Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth...
"Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth...
where moths and rust do corrupt and where thieves break through and steal.
"where moths and rust do corrupt and where thieves break through and steal.
But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven...
"But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven...
where neither moth nor rust corrupt...
"where neither moth nor rust corrupt...
and where thieves do not break through and steal.
"and where thieves do not break through and steal.
For where your treasure is, there shall your heart be also.
"For where your treasure is, there shall your heart be also.
I know that my redeemer liveth...
- "I know that my redeemer liveth...
Whom I shall see for myself and mine eyes shall behold.
"Whom I shall see for myself and mine eyes shall behold.
Be not deceived. God is not mocked.
"Be not deceived. God is not mocked.
For whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.
"For whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.
Bob, Bob, Bob, Bob Bob-Bob-Bob-Bob
Bob-Bob-Bob
Bob, Bob, Bob Bob, Bob, Bob
Bob-Bob-Bob-Bob-Bob
Bob, Bob, Bob
For he that soweth to his flesh, shall of the flesh reap corruption.
"For he that soweth to his flesh, shall of the flesh reap corruption.
Bob, Bob-Bob
Bob!
鲍勃！
Bob! Bob! Bob!
鲍勃！鲍勃！鲍勃！
But he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit...
"But he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit...
reap life everlasting.
"reap life everlasting.
And let us not be weary in well-doing, for in due season...
"And let us not be weary in well-doing; for in due season-
Bob! Bob! Bob!
鲍勃！鲍勃！鲍勃！
And their going from us to be utter destruction."
And their going from us to be utter destruction. "
Bob! Bob! Bob!
鲍勃！鲍勃！鲍勃！
George!
乔治！
I'm a connoisseur of roads.
我是路的行家。
Been tasting roads my whole life.
一生品尝路的滋味。
This road... will never end.
这条路...永无止境。
It probably goes... all around... the world.
也许它环绕着整个世界。
剧终 谢谢观赏
When I first came to London
I was only 16
With a fiver in my pocket
And my old dancing bag
I went down to the dilly
To check out the scene
But I soon ended up upon the old main drag
Where the he-males and the she-males
Paraded in style
And the old man with the money would flash you a smile
In the dark of an alley you would work for a five
For a swift one off the wrist down on the old main drag
In the cold winter nights the old town it was chill
But there were boys in the cafés
Who'd give you cheap pills
If you didn't have the money
You'd cajole and you'd beg
There was always lots of Tuinal
On the old main drag
One evening as I was lying
Down in Leicester Square
I was picked up by the coppers
And kicked in the balls
Between the metal doors at Vine Street
I was beaten and mauled
And they ruined my good looks
For the old main drag
In the tube station
The old ones who were on the way out
Would dribble and vomit
And grovel and shout
And the coppers would come along
And push them about
And I wished I could escape from
The old main drag
And now I am lying here
I have had too much booze
I've been spat on and shat on
And raped and abused
I know that I am dying and I wish I could beg
For some money to take me from the old main drag
Deep night
Stars in the sky above
Moonlight
Lighting our place of love
Night winds
Seem to have gone to rest
Two eyes
Brightly with love are gleaming
Come to my arms, my dear one
My sweetheart, my own
Vow that you'll love me always
And be mine alone
Deep night
Whispering trees above
Kind night
Bringing you nearer, dearer and dearer
Deep night
Deep in the arms
Of love